Please continue to
watch over Shouquan
See that he doesn't get choked
on elixirs again. Thank you
Don't believe in the elixir
Joined Brow is only a robber.
He isn't a divine physician at all
Swordswoman, you're here!
Please have a seat!
Pour her some water
You've done us a really big favour,
Swordswoman
She's your saviour
Had it not been for her,
you'd long have died
How can we thank you enough?
-I must say you're a living buddha
-A living buddha?
It's thanks to
that cursed Zhang Guolao...
My mother is praising you.
What are you mumbling about?
Nothing
-How are you?
-I'm a lot better
Thanks for saving my life
Don't mention it.
You have a lot to thank me for
I beg your pardon?
I mean, he has the looks of a blessed
man, so he's bound to come to no harm
That's where you're wrong.
Don't be deceived by his looks
He may look strong and fit,
but he's actually a very unlucky man
He's always having stomachaches
or passing out
Had you not saved him this time,
he'd long have gone to meet his Maker
You're indeed Shou's saviour,
Swordswoman
Don't keep calling me Swordswoman.
It's rather embarrassing
We'll address you as Miss Ma then.
Miss Ma, what's your full name?
It's...
Miss Ma?
Just call me Ruyi
Ruyi?
That's a good name
Everything will go well (ruyi)
for Shou when he's with you
Let's all kowtow to Miss Ma Ruyi
for having saved Shou
No need for that. I can't keep saving
him. He must learn to save himself
-Save myself?
-Save himself?
From today on, you're to build yourself
up according to the instructions here
Martial arts?
Surely not?
Miss Ma, he knows nothing
about martial arts
That's why he has to learn it
You're weak because there's no routine
in your life. You have to change
By practising the Five-Animal Exercise,
you'll have good brains, a strong heart,
flexible joints and healthy kidneys
I'm not interested in martial arts
You must master it by the age of 30
no matter what!
By the age of 30?!
Why?
Is it because you know
my son won't live pass 30?
Just entrust him to me and I assure you
he'll live to a ripe old age
Really?
Sure, if he practises 4 hours each
in the morning, afternoon and evening
So many hours? How would I
find time to eat and sleep then?
Don't interrupt.
Hear Miss Ma out
You eat and sleep too much, and work
too little. That's why you're so weak
You're to kick those bad habits
And memorize all the strokes in the
book before you sleep every night...
to facilitate next day's training
-I'll check every 3 days
-Check?
To make sure you're working hard.
I'll be standing by you
What?
You can't be serious
Till you've mastered the exercise
You've taken the words out of my mouth,
Miss Ma! Please take him in hand for me
He may be 28, but he still
behaves like a child
He isn't as easy to handle
as my little niece
But don't be scared off by him
I won't be. When he was born,
he peed at me right in the face
What? I peed at you in the face?
I mean my little brother is as naughty
as him. He also pees everywhere
So I'm leaving my son with you
Ma-jiejie, you're so good to my uncle.
I'll treat you to tangguan
Sure
Can you tell me why
you're wearing a veil?
Can I see your face?
All right
What are you packing for?
Young Master wants to set off earlier
-Did he say that himself?
-Yes
He even studied till
late in the night
Really?
Son, I heard you're setting off
for the Capital earlier
I can't wait to get to the Capital
After that?
-I'll excel in the exams
-Good
I'll be the top scholar...
and take over the entire yamen
Good! You have ambition!
After that?
I'll become the master of Golden
Swallow, the No 1 lady constable!
I'll prove myself to her!
You're studying just because you
want to prove yourself to that woman?
What a disgrace you are!
Do you know how she humiliated me?
I'm a man. I can't possibly
take that lying down
As the saying goes, "If a dragon falls,
it's no different from a worm"
"A water dragon on dry land
is same as a fish out of water"
I can't stand being looked down on
by a woman!
So it's actually a woman
who made you, a man,
go to the Capital
Young Master!
I'm human. Why should I imitate
the actions of these animals?
I quit!
I'm surprised you know
how to fly too
Can you teach me?
You can do it too if you
master the Five-Animal Exercise
You must be joking.
Me, flying, given my size?
Hold it there!
Come on, don't waste your effort.
I'm so heavy. How can I possibly fly?
It's utterly impossible, right?
-How much have you grasped?
-I've finished the whole book
-Do you understand everything then?
-Not one bit of it
Chest out!
I want you to do a stance!
Ma...
Be quiet and concentrate on
your exercise
What I mean is, my legs are numb (ma)
It happens when you
practise martial arts
Before assigning big tasks to you,
Heaven will put you through the mill
-Surely you've learnt that in school?
-Yes
But are you doing that? No.
You've lived in vain for 28 years!
Indeed. I can only see white
in front of me now...
Wait till you're used to such training.
You'll become fitter
It beats your mother's solution
to get you a wife
I really need to lean
against a big tree...
What's the matter?
I sometimes have giddy spells
even when I'm resting at home
You expect me to stay in this position
for hours. I might just drop dead
How feeble can you be!
Get up!
Stop pretending!
What's the meaning of this?!
Why did you ask us out, Lu?
It's like this.
I'll be away for some time
Why?
I'm going to the Capital to sit
the imperial exam. So farewell
I say, this is more novel than
Shou being made to learn martial arts
Didn't you vow never to step into
an examination hall? Why are you...?
What happened?
Shou is forced to learn martial arts.
That's rather normal
But you're going to the Capital
to sit the exams. That's strange
Are you a changed person?
Why?
I've got it! Don't tell me
it was Ma Ruyi who made you go
Speak the truth, quick!
The very mention of Ma Ruyi
makes me mad! She's too much!
I must top the exams
and teach her a lesson!
See if she dares be so arrogant again
Is Golden Swallow this incredible?
She's actually got you under her thumb!
You two are really useless!
Don't laugh at us. We're the Trio.
She'll come to you sooner or later
I have a feeling you'll be
her next target
I'm not afraid of her! If she comes,
she's going to get it from me!
Make way!
You've been following me.
What do you want?
I'm here specially for you
Going to ask me to learn martial arts
before I turn 30?
Oh please! I'm not going to
imitate the actions of animals
Neither am I a man of letters.
Don't expect me to sit the imperial exams
Relax. You're so bright
I won't have to teach you
Glad you know that
You only have to promise
not to do these again!
The 10 Commandments?
That's right. Kick all these
bad habits before you're 30
No gambling, no fighting,
no lying, no engaging in flattery...
No robbing, no stealing, no cheating
No idling,
no indulging in women and wine
Last one -
no seeing of Joined Brow again!
Why?
Mei Shouquan and Wei Delu aren't doing
what they should but you're the opposite
That's why you must kick
all your bad habits!
I'm asking you why
I can't see my teacher again
Why stick with that robber? Going to
learn to commit crimes from him?
He who lies with dogs
will rise with fleas
He was forced to become an outlaw.
He's actually a Robin Hood
He got you to help him get Gem-faced
Leopard out and you still believe him?
That shows he's a worthy friend
who treasures friendship
I don't believe this
Were you scared dumb by the God of Plague
when you were born? Let me have a look
You're the God of Plague!
He nearly caused your buddy's death,
you know!
You were the one at fault, not him!
Me?
Had you not expelled the pill,
Shou would've recovered completely
He isn't worthy of teaching at all
Well, don't bother to teach me then.
You're not cut out for it
I suggest you get married quickly
Don't look too fierce or behave like
a shrew, or you'll be left on the shelf
I don't mind settling for you though
I'm still a bachelor anyway
No engaging in flattery
How dare you hit me!
I'll get you for this!
Memorize the 10 Commandments or else!
Help...!
Come and have a look
at this disobedient lad...!
Did you put away the book
I passed you last night?
-Where's the book I passed you?
-When did you pass me any book?
I passed it to you last night
No, you didn't
-I passed it to you
-And I passed it to you before turning in
He passed it to you
Young Master, all our books are gone
I'd rather you two were gone!
Fancy losing my books!
Fancy you forgetting your books. I even
have to go back to get them for you
Young Master...
Young Master...!
I didn't do it on purpose...!
What happened?!
Young Master...
You gave me a scare!
You won't let me see my teacher?
Well, I'm going to do just that!
Wait till I've learnt a skill or two
from Teacher! I'll get even with you!
I'll tie you and hang you up
on the city gate!
You need to be taught a lesson or you
won't be able to tell right from wrong
My dear teacher! Your dear disciple,
Wu Fuqi, has come to look for you!
My dear teacher!
So you really have ganged up
with Golden Swallow on me!
You're asking for it!
I'll send you to your Makers today!
My dear teacher!
You're no disciple of mine!
I'm over here... Come on,
I'll send you to the nether world...
Let me give you hell first!
Teacher...!
Stop there!
-It's you!
-That's right! You should thank me!
My foot!
The last time, you tied me up
Now you tried to crush me with rocks!
And you expect me to thank you?!
I tried to crush you?
Joined Brow...
Oh, it was my teacher
you tried to harm
Let me tell you - he's shrewd.
He's long hidden himself
No way will you be able to
trick him. Fool!
Why did you slap me?
I told you you're not to see your teacher
again! The slap was to remind you!
My dear, it's my business that...
I'm abandoning myself to vice
and that I'm good-for-nothing
Lu and Shou are more promising than me.
Why not spend time on them instead?
Thanks
I will take them in hand.
But you're not exempted!
Remember to copy the 10 Commandments
100 times every morning!
-100 times?! You're crazy!
-I'll be watching you!
Why is my face so itchy?
What are you looking at?!
Don't you misbehave! I have to go!
What a shrew she is!
Would I dare misbehave
with you around?
Oh Heaven, please help me!
Strike her to death by lightning!
What did you say?!
My sister Ma-gu!
Good timing. Look at my face.
Do I look awful?
Indeed you have some freckles on
your face. But they aren't obvious
And they'll go off in 3 days
I have to wait 3 days?
Oh, see how ugly I look!
Who told you to use your powers?
Well, I'm an immortal. What has that
to do with my freckles anyway?
Everything!
If you want to subdue some demon to save
the people, you may use your powers
But you're not supposed to use them
to save the Trio
But why? They're mortals now.
Why can't I use my powers to save them?
Just think. They're sent to the
mortal world because they've sinned
They must suffer 3 ordeals, 6 hardships
and 8 tribulations before they can return
If you use your powers to ward off
all the disasters for them,
you'll be going against the Jade Emperor
and will be punished!
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Had I told you, would you still
be willing to go to the mortal world?
So you tricked me.
I'm washing my hands of the Trio!
You can't quit halfway. You must stay
in the mortal world to help them
When they return, you'll become their
guardian deity. Isn't that good?
You just want me to stay
in the mortal world
Oh yes, why is there a Golden Swallow?
Why does everyone take me for her?
She isn't in my plan
People might have mistaken you for her
when you helped the Trio
All the better. You can use her
as a cover to hide your real identity
You must never reveal you're an immortal
But of course.
I'm not so stupid
Good. Carry on your duty
as Golden Swallow
Besides guarding the Trio,
I still have to be a constable?
There's no turning back now.
Just do it
Look!
This is Yurong Paste from Chang E
And this is Xianlu lotion
from He Xiangu
Apply them on your face. Your freckles
will go off in less than 3 days
I specially got them for you, you know
Aren't you resourceful. I've asked Chang
E for it a few times but was turned down
Get me a few more bottles next time
I won't have to worry about my complexion
however bad the mortal environment is
The constables risked their lives
and found this piece of evidence
What have you go to say?
Your Excellency, that isn't mine...
Why were the bombs put in your chest
of all the chests then?
I don't know
I do! You're in cahoots
with Joined Brow!
Men, take her back with us!
I'm innocent...!
You're back, Wu Fuqi.
I thought you'd gone into hiding
She's innocent.
Let her go
If she's innocent,
you must be guilty then
Indeed the bombs were mine.
My mother was in the dark. Let her go
You're saying you collaborated
with Joined Brow?
That's right. I'm responsible for
everything. Arrest me if you must
Aren't you free, young man
You don't understand
Studying frantically at the last minute
isn't going to help at all
You sound rather conceited
I suppose you read widely and are
confident in coming out top in the exam?
Reading is interesting
but exams are meaningless
All the more so when the person
marking your paper is of low calibre
Why did you still come here then?
It's my father's wish I sit the exams.
This is a piece of cake to me anyway
So I just humour him
Let me tell you frankly.
I hate officials
They're nothing but toadies
who sit on the fence!
-You know who that man was?
-Who was he?
My uncle Zha Daoguang,
nicknamed Blink Blink
All-sucked-up (zha dao guang)?
So?
He's the chief examiner this year
-You're Wei Delu?
-Yes. It's written in there
Where are you from?
It's written in there
Did you drop from Heaven or
did you come out from the ground?
There's no such place
This is the character "yu"
It's "yu" as in stupidity,
benightedness, and ignorance
I was born here. They've changed the name
of the place. This is no longer used
Since it no longer exists,
where are you from?
You can't be more dull.
I won't argue with you
Doubtful background. He's disqualified
from sitting the exams! Take him away!
Blame it on your ignorance!
I want to see the Chief Examiner!
Quiet!
Are you all right, Young Master?
Yes
Why cover your face?
Too ashamed to face anyone?
Speak for yourself.
You're forever wearing a veil
Shouldn't you be sitting your exam?
Did you offend someone again?
I only argued strongly
on just ground
Didn't I tell you to
watch your tongue?
I didn't say anything wrong.
Not sitting the exam is no big deal
If you miss it this year, you'll have
to wait so long for the next one!
I'm the one sitting the exams, not you.
Why are you so worked up?
All three of you are incorrigible!
Abracadabra...!
Luck is with me and not you!
Small!
There goes your meat. Sorry!
-Take him to the cell next door
-Yes, Madam!
Where are you taking him?
Just what do you want?
Why did you take him away?
I'll inform Magistrate Shi. Isn't it
better now that there's more room?
Have you done your homework?
-What homework?
-Memorize the 10 Commandments
The 10 Commandments?
You tore it up?!
It's in shreds now.
Feel disheartened, eh?
Since you like gambling so much,
let's have a bet
Sure! But what will I
stand to gain if I win?
If I lose, you'll get 10 taels.
How's that?
You're on!
I bet that you can't finish copying
the 10 Commandments before sunset
Can you tell me
what the 10 commandments are?
Isn't it on the floor?
Such illegible handwriting!
You never said I had to write neatly.
I've won. Now you mustn't welsh on me
All right, you win today.
I'll come back tomorrow
Whatever for?
To gamble with you again.
Are you scared?
Of course not!
You're on!
One for you, one for me
Why did you hit me?
I told you to practise your exercise!
But I did. I practised for 2 hours and
felt hungry, so I came here with Jiujin
Right?
-Is that so?
-Yes
I'm showing good progress.
See how strong I've become
Look at my muscles.
I can even kill two tigers
You're breaking my arm!
Let go!
You have no strength at all!
Do you do the exercise or not?!
Yes... I've memorized the strokes, but
I have a weak foundation, that's why
Not so hard, please...
You've memorized the strokes?
Recite them to me then
-What's the first line?
-Too tense to do it off hand?
Yes... You're so understanding
Take out the book and see then
The book...?
Jiujin, where's the book?
You've even forgotten the book?
It must be in my study...
I found this in a drain near your house.
You actually threw it away!
Don't you dare hit me again!
We aren't related at all.
Why do you keep hitting me?
If you like to teach so much, just
grab any man and bear him children!
You can teach them any way
you like then! Leave me alone!
Let's go!
Why, you...!
I need a sedan!
-Let me carry you
-No, I'll go home on my own
You're not going anywhere!
This doesn't concern you.
You may go
Wait! Take me home.
I'll pay you 10 wen more
I'll give you 1 tael.
Leave this minute
Thanks!
Did I do you wrong in a previous life?
Why do you keep antagonizing me?
Your house is only a stone's throw away
yet you didn't even want to walk!
Go on like this and your health
will deteriorate!
You mean me well.
I appreciate your kindness
You may go.
I'll walk home
You don't trust me?
Bearers...!
Why didn't you wait for me?
Let's go
-You had me on!
-So what?
-Move on...
-No! Get off!
Move on!
-Get off!
-No!
I said get off!
Building roads and bridges
is a good deed indeed! Bah!
She's just like the tofu
Ma-po is selling
What's the connection between them?
Hot and spicy -
doesn't that describe her best?
So you've been antagonizing her.
No wonder she's always picking on you
And I suffer as a result
See, they don't have to do anything
This isn't fair at all!
Spicy woman, it's unfair!
Why do we have to do all these chores
while they can lie idle?
Your duty is to build roads and bridges
while theirs is to raise funds
This is division of labour
Indeed!
You don't allocate work evenly!
We're toiling but
they don't even need to sweat!
I see nothing wrong with that.
What do you want?
I want to join them
It's tough raising funds. Don't say
I didn't warn you. Don't regret it
I won't!
Go...
No skiving!
Get cracking!
We weren't skiving. Nobody passes by.
What can we do?
This place is deserted. It's no point
coming up with good ideas
Is that so?
But I think if an idea is good,
there will be no lack of donations
Just what is she up to?
They were right. Anybody who sticks
with you will end up in a bad patch!
Attention, everybody!
These people are criminals
They've committed heinous crimes
Today, they're casting
their pride and ego aside,
and exposing themselves to ridicule
so as to raise funds for public use
Listen good! If you donate 1 wen,
you can throw stones at them
For 3 wen,
you can throw cow dung at them
And for 5 wen,
you can throw rotten eggs!
Wretched woman! If I ever get my hands
on you, I'll strip you and parade you!
You bad woman!
You'll be left on the shelf!
If I ever get a chance,
I'll get back at you!
Wait till you're able to do that
I already told you it wasn't easy to
raise funds but you didn't believe me
Who can you blame?
Cut the crap!
We need to go back to jail to wash
Hurry!
Who says you can go back? The money
isn't enough. You must work night shift
We're filthy and you still think
we didn't raise enough money?!
You think you're worth a lot?
Every throw was only a few wen
How much are you short of?
I'll go and rob
We're 10 taels short.
Get me the money if you're so capable
Didn't you tell me this morning
you had 10 taels?
Did I? I was only joking.
I don't have it
I heard you distinctly
No... Like you said,
I couldn't possibly have 10 taels
Yes, you do. I lost 10 taels to you
the other day, remember?
You can't have spent it
since you're in jail
Take out the money, buddy. I'll
take you along the next time I rob
You can have all the money
you want then
You ought to respect
your teacher's fellow disciple too
All right, I'll take out the money!
Spicy woman! Darn you!
Just you wait!
What a spread! It's been ages
since I last had such delicacies!
-Uncle!
-Come, Jiujin
There's a lot of food.
What would you like?
Going to take my food away?
Sorry about the other day.
I'm here to offer my apologies
Knowing you're a gourmet,
I've prepared some goodies for you
Would you be so kind?
What are the goodies?
You're weak.
These dishes are no good for you
Chunhua, take them away
The chicken is too fat, and the stewed
duck, too "cold". Take them away too
You have a weak stomach.
No sour food either
-Jiujin
-Yes, Ma-jiejie?
Uncle can't eat this.
Can you take it away?
I can't even eat fish?
Cool down and see what
I've cooked for you
Veg with dried lizards,
steamed silkworms,
lotus soup with seahorses,
and stewed centipedes!
Are all these edible?
Mother...!
Mother!
What are you screaming for?
You're making yourself a laughing-stock
Look what food she's giving me!
She's trying to poison me to death!
Miss Ma...
These are medicated dishes
I've prepared for your son
Medicated dishes?
Seahorses, centipedes, silkworms and
lizards will all help to build him up
If he takes them on a long-term basis
and also does the Five-Animal Exercise,
he'll recover without medication
Don't believe her, Mother.
We don't know her background at all
And she wants me to imitate animals.
What's her motive?
Now she even wants me to eat these!
She's obviously up to no good!
Nonsense! It's recorded in ancient books
these things can be used as medicines
You can check them up
And if we exchange pointers on the Five-
Animal Exercise, you'll know what I mean
You're well-versed in martial arts.
I'm no match for you
I won't be the one taking you on
but Jiujin!
Jiujin?!
Just give her a hard punch!
I'm not so stupid! She weighs 9 jin
and I, 190 jin. What if I kill her?
She isn't afraid at all
Right?
Now, don't get me into trouble
All right, here I go
Jiujin, how did you do that?
Well done!
I only taught her a stroke from the
Exercise this morning and she beat you
The Five-Animal Exercise was invented
by Hua Tuo. It's best for weak people
Practising the basic strokes
builds you up
If you learn more, the Exercise
can even be used for self-defence
It enables weak people to counter
strong opponents with little strength
That was how Jiujin beat you
Miss Ma, you're really good to Shou.
From now on, we'll do everything you say
I'll throw away all the medicines,
and see that Shou practises
the Exercise and eats these dishes
Where's justice...?
Is it you, Teacher?
-Where's Gem-faced Leopard?
-They've put him in another cell
Brother, I'm over here!
I've come to get you out!
Do it, quick!
Let's get out of here first
Quick!
-Golden Swallow! Fu, did you...
-Nothing of the sort!
This is none of your business!
Get lost!
I'll never let you leave with them!
Come on,
it's not as if I were your son!
It's fake!
Subtitled by S Lin